(酒馆)
(旅馆)
(悬赏,五十兆亿元)
All right, everyone! This... is a stick- up!
大家给我听好,这是抢劫
Don't anybody move!
通通都不准动
(银行  杂货店)
Now, empty that safe!
把猪扑满给我掏空
Money, money, money!
钱钱钱
Stop it! Stop it, you mean, old potato!
住手,住手!你这可恶的蛋头
Quiet, Bo Peep, or your sheep get run over!
闭嘴,宝贝,否则你的羊会遭殃
Help! Baa! Help us!
救命,救命啊
Oh, no, not my sheep! Somebody do something!
别伤害我的羊,谁来帮帮忙啊
Reach for the sky!
飞向天空
Oh, no! Sheriff Woody!
糟了,是胡迪警长
I'm here to stop you, One- Eyed Bart.
我是来阻止你的,独眼蛋头
How'd you know it was me?
你怎么知道是我啊?
Are you gonna come quietly?
乖乖跟我走吧
You can't touch me, Sheriff!
你休想,警长
I brought my attack dog with the built- in force field.
我带了我那只,凶狠的斗犬来了
Well, I brought my dinosaur who eats force- field dogs.
我带了我的恐龙,它专门吃凶狠的斗犬
Yipe, yipe, yipe, yipe! You're going to jail, Bart!
你要去坐牢了,蛋头
Say goodbye to the wife and Tater Tots.
跟你老婆小孩说再见吧
(监狱)
You saved the day again, Woody.
你又解救了危机,胡迪
You're my favorite deputy.
你是我最喜欢的副警长
《玩具总动员》
∮ You've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 你什么也别愁 ∮
Come on, let's wrangle up the cattle.
来,我们来抓牛吧
∮ When the road looks rough ahead ∮
∮ 道路坎坷困难多 ∮
∮ And you're miles and miles from your nice warm bed ∮
∮ 要十万八千里才到家门口 ∮
Round 'em up, cowboy!
牛仔,把他们围起来
∮ Just remember what your old pal said ∮
∮ 你只要想起我在你左右 ∮
∮ Boy you've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 我是你好朋友 ∮
Yee- haw!
呀啊!
∮ Yeah you've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 哦对,我是你好朋友 ∮
Hey, cowboy!
嗨,牛仔
∮ Some other folks might be a little bit smarter than I am ∮
∮ 有些人比我能干比我强 ∮
∮ Big and stronger too ∮
∮ 身体健壮走起路雄赳赳 ∮
Come on, Woody.
来吧,胡迪
∮ Maybe ∮
∮ 也许 ∮
∮ But none of them will ever love you the way I do ∮
∮ 没有人能像我这样爱护你 ∮
∮ It's me and you boy ∮
∮ 对你是毫无保留 ∮
∮ And as the years go by ∮
∮ 多少的岁月中 ∮
Whoa! Whoa!
哇!哇!
∮ Our friendship will never die ∮
∮ 我们的命运紧相连 ∮
∮ You're gonna see It's our destiny ∮
∮ 我们的友谊更加深厚 ∮
∮ You've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 我是你好朋友 ∮
All right!
好耶
∮ Yeah you've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 哦对,我是你好朋友 ∮
Score!
达阵得分
- ∮ You got a friend in me ∮ - ∮ Wow! Cool! ∮
- ∮ 我是你好朋友 ∮ - ∮ 酷毙了 ∮
- What do you think? - Oh, this looks great, Mom!
- 你喜欢吗? - 妈咪,这真是太棒了
Okay, birthday boy...
你喜欢就好,小寿星
We saw that at the store! I asked you for it!
就跟我在店里看到的一样
- I hope I have enough places. - Wow, look at that! That's so...
- 好棒,好棒哦... - 希望能摆得下
- One, two... Four. - Oh, my gosh, you got...
- 一,二,三,四 - 哦，天哪，你有...
- Yeah, I think that's gonna be enough. - Could we leave this up 'til we move?
- 很好,这样应该就夠了 - 可以留到搬家吗?
- Well, sure! We can leave it up. - Yeah!
- 当然可以啰 - 好耶
Now go get Molly. Your friends are gonna be here any minute.
去抱茉莉,你的朋友马上就要来了
Okay. It's party time, Woody.
好,派对要开始了
Yee... haw!
呀啊!
(安弟的房间  闲人勿进)
Howdy, little lady.
你好,小妹妹
Somebody's poisoned the water hole.
有人在水源区下了毒
Come on, Molly.
来吧,茉莉!
Oh, you're getting heavy.
你好重哦
See you later, Woody.
再见了,胡迪
Pull my string! The birthday party's today?
我的天哪,是今天开生日派对吗?
Okay, everybody, coast is clear!
好了,各位,已经安全了
Ages 3 and up. It's on my box...
我盒子上写得很清楚,适合三岁以上
Ages 3 and up. I'm not supposed to be baby- sitting Princess Drool.
怎么能叫我当,口水公主的临时褓姆呢
Hey, Hamm.
火腿,你看!
- Look, I'm Picasso! - I don't get it.
- 我是毕加索 - 我看不懂
You uncultured swine! What're you lookin' at, ya hockey puck?
没有文化的肥猪,看什么看啊!你这个大扁脸
- Hey, Sarge, have you seen Slinky? - Sir! No, sir!
- 队长,看到弹簧狗没有 - 报告长官,没有
Okay. Hey, thank you. At ease.
好啦,谢了!稍息
Hey, uh, Slinky?
弹簧狗
Right here, Woody. I'm red this time.
我在这儿,胡迪,这次我要红的
- No. Slink... - Oh, well, all right.
- 不行,弹簧狗... - 好吧!
You can be red if you want.
那红的让给你好了,等一下,弹簧狗
- Not now, Slink. I got some bad news. - Bad news?
- 我有一些坏消息 - 坏消息,嘘...
Just gather everyone up for a staff meeting, and be happy.
去叫大家集合来开干部会议,装得开心一点
Got it.
知道了
Be happy!
装得开心一点
Staff meeting, everybody! Snake, Robot, podium duty.
各位,要开干部会议,长蛇,机器人准备讲台
Hey.
喂
Hey, Etch. Draw!
嘿,画板,拔枪
Oh! Got me again.
你又赢了
Etch, you've been working on that draw. Fastest knobs in the West.
画板,你拔枪练得不错嘛,西部最快的神枪手
Got a staff meeting, you guys. Come on, let's go.
大伙儿要开干部会议了,来吧,快点
Now, where is that... Oh.
我的那个呢?
Hey, who moved my doodle pad way over here?
谁把我涂鸦板拿走的
- How're you doin', Rex? - Were you scared? Tell me honestly.
- 抱抱龙,你好吗? - 你有没有被吓到?说实话
I was close to being scared that time.
这一次,我差一点就被你吓死
I'm going for fearsome here, but I just don't feel it.
我一直想可怕一点,但是我老是没有灵感
I think I'm just coming off as annoying.
我只是一个惹人厌的傢伙
Oh, hi, Bo. Hi.
嗨,宝贝
I wanted to thank you, Woody, for saving my flock.
胡迪,我想要谢谢你救了我的羊群
Oh, hey, it was, uh, nothin'.
不客气
What do you say I get someone else to watch the sheep tonight?
我今天晚上另外找个人,替我看羊,你看怎么样啊
Oh, yeah!
这个嘛,好啊
Remember, I'm just a couple of blocks away.
别忘了,要找我的话,我就在附近
- Yodel-ay-hee-hoo! - Come on, come on.
- 呦啊嘿吼 - 快点,快点
Smaller toys up front.
小的玩具到前面
Hey, Woody, come on.
胡迪,来吧
(组装玩具)
Oh, thanks, Mike.
谢了,麦克风
Okay... Whoa whoa. Step back.
好了,太近了,退后...
- For crying out loud. - Thank you.
- 拜托 - 好了,谢谢
Hello? Check. That better? Great.
试音,试音,清楚吗?
Everybody hear me? Up on the shelf, can you hear me? Great.
好,大家都听到了吗?架子上面的听见吗?很好
Okay. First item today:
今天我们第一项议题
Oh, yeah. Has everyone picked a moving buddy?
对了!每个人都找到,搬家伙伴了没有?
- What? - Moving buddy? You can't be serious.
- 什么? - 搬家伙伴?他不是说真的吧?
I didn't know we were supposed to have one already.
我不知道我们要搬家了
Do we have to hold hands?
我们要拉小手吗?
You guys think this is a big joke.
你们以为,我在跟你们开玩笑
We've only got one week left before the move.
我们只剩下一个礼拜的时间,就要搬家了
I don't want any toys left behind. A moving buddy.
我不希望任何玩具被丢下来,两个人一组
If you don't have one, get one!
如果还没有搬家伙伴,去找一个来!
All right, next. Oh, yes.
好了,接下来...对了!
Tuesday night's plastic corrosion awareness meeting
星期二晚上,我们开的塑胶老化大会
was, I think, a big success.
我认为呢,非常的成功
And we wanna thank Mr. Spell for putting that on for us.
我们要感谢拼字先生,为我们所做的一切
- Thank you, Mr. Spell. - You're welcome.
- 谢谢你,拼字先生 - 不客气
Okay. Oh, yes. One minor note here.
好了!对了,还有一件小事
Andy's birthday party has been moved to today.
安弟的生日派对,改到今天晚上
Wait a minute here!
接下来我们要讨论的是...什么?
What do you mean the party's today? His birthday's not 'til next week!
怎么会改成今天呢?下个礼拜才是他的生日啊
What's goin' on down there? Is his mom losin' her marbles?
搞什么鬼?安弟的妈咪头壳坏去了吗?
Well, obviously she wanted to have the party before the move.
很显然安弟的妈咪,希望在搬家之前开一个派对
I'm not worried. You shouldn't be worried.
我不担心,你们也不需要担心啊
Of course Woody ain't worried. He's been Andy's favorite since kindergarten.
胡迪当然不担心了,安弟从幼稚园开始,就最喜欢他了
Hey, hey. Come on, Potato Head.
拜托,蛋头先生
If Woody says it's all right, then, well, darn it, it's good enough for me.
如果胡迪说不用担心,那么我绝对不会担心
Woody has never steered us wrong before.
胡迪以前从来没有弄错过
Come on, guys. Every Christmas and birthday we go through this.
拜托,各位,每年圣诞节,和生日我们都熬过来了
But what if Andy gets another dinosaur, a mean one?
但是如果安弟有了新恐龙呢,很凶狠的那一种
I just don't think I could take that kind of rejection!
我想我是绝对受不了,被抛弃的打击
Hey, listen, no one's getting replaced.
听着!没有人可以取代我们
This is Andy we're talking about.
我们讨论的重点是安弟
It doesn't matter how much we're played with.
我们和安弟玩,多少次并不重要
What matters is that we're here for Andy when he needs us.
重要的是安弟需要我们的时候,我们都在他身边
That's what we're made for, right?
那才是我们当玩具的目的,对吧?
Pardon me. I hate to break up the staff meeting, but... they're here!
对不起哦,我很不想打断会议,但是...他们来了!
Birthday guests at three o'clock!
客人在三点钟方向
Stay calm, everyone!
保持冷静
Hey!
喂!
Meeting adjourned.
会议结束
Ho, boy! Will you take a look at all those presents?
老天!你们有没有看到那些礼物?
I can't see a thing.
我什么都看不到
Yes, sir, we're next month's garage sale fodder for sure.
我们绝对会是,下个月车库拍卖的货品了
- Any dinosaur- shaped ones? - Oh, for crying out loud.
- 有没有恐龙形状的礼物啊? - 哦,谢谢你大声哭出来
- They're all in box. Es, you idiot. - They're getting bigger.
- 拜托,礼物都在盒子里!白痴 - 礼物越来越大了
Wait, there's a nice little one over there.
等一等,那里有个小件的
Hi!
嗨!
We're doomed!
我们完了
All right! All right!
好啦,好啦
If I send out the troops, will you all calm down?
如果我派部队出去的话,你们能安静下来吗?
- Yes! Yes! We promise! - Okay! Save your batteries.
- 能,能,我们保证 - 好,省省电池吧
Very good, Woody. That's using the old noodle.
帅哟,胡迪,这一招真有效
Sergeant, establish a recon post downstairs. Code Red!
队长,立刻派侦察队到楼下,紧急状况
- You know what to do. - Yes, sir!
- 你知道该怎么做 - 是,长官
All right, men. You heard him. Code Red!
好了,各位,你们都听到了,紧急状况
Repeat, we are at Code Red. Recon plan Charlie. Ex. Ecute!
重复,紧急状况,侦察计划开始执行
Let's move! Move, move, move, move!
快...快...
(绿色奇兵)
Yeah!
好耶!
Okay, come on, kids.
好了,小朋友们
Everyone in the living room. It's almost time for the presents.
所有的人都到客厅来,准备要拆礼物了
All right, gangway, gangway.
让开,让开
And this is how we find out
有了这玩意儿,我们就可以知道
what is in those presents.
那些礼物是什么了
Okay, who's hungry?
好了,谁的肚子饿了?
Here come the chips!
洋芋片在这里
I've got Cool Ranch and barbecue!
有原味还有烤肉口味的
What in the world... Oh!
噢!怎么搞的?
I thought I told him to pick these up.
我还以为他收拾干净了呢
Shouldn't they be there by now? What's taking them so long?
他们不是该到了吗?怎么会那么久?
Hey, these guys are professionals. They're the best.
他们可是训练有素,最优秀的军人
Come on! They're not lying down on the job.
放心啦,他们并没有躺着偷懒
Go on without me! Just go!
走吧,别管我了!快走吧
A good soldier never leaves a man behind.
一个好军人,绝对不会丢下战友
Okay, everybody, come on.
好了,小朋友,夠了
Everybody settle down. Now, kids. Everybody...
大家都坐好,好了,小朋友,快过来
You sit in a circle. No, Andy. Andy, you sit in the middle there.
围成圈圈坐下来,不,安弟,你要坐中间
Good. And... Which present are you gonna open first?
很好,好,你想先拆哪一个礼物呢?
- Mine! - There they are.
- 我的 - 他们在那儿
Come in Mother Bird. This is Alpha Bravo.
大鸟妈妈请回答,这是B队队长
- This is it! This is it! Quiet, quiet! - Come in Mother Bird.
- 大鸟妈妈请回答 - 有消息了,大家安静
All right Andy's opening the first present now.
好了,安弟正在拆第一个礼物了
Mrs. Potato Head! Mrs. Potato Head! Mrs. Potato Head!
蛋头太太,蛋头太太...
Hey, I can dream, can't I?
做白日梦又不犯法
The bow's coming off. He's ripping the wrapping paper.
缎带被解开了,他正在拆包装纸
It's a... It's... It's a... a lunch bo.
那是...那是...那是一个便当盒
- We've got a lunch bo here. - A lunch box?
- 那是一个便当盒 - 便当盒?
- Lunch box? - For lunch.
- 便当盒 - 午餐
Okay second present. It appears to be...
好了,第二个礼物,那看起来是...
- Okay it's bed sheets. - Who invited that kid?
- 一件床单 - 那小子谁请来的呀?
Oh! Only one left.
只剩下一个了
- Okay we're on the last present now. - Last present!
- 好,接着是最后一个礼物了 - 最后一个了
It's a big one. It's a...
这个礼物很大,那...
- It's a board game! Repeat Battleship! - Whew!
- 那是棋盘游戏 - 重复,是海战棋
Hallelujah!
好耶,好耶
- Yeah! All right! - Hey, watch it!
- 耶 好的 - 小心一点
Sorry there, old spud head.
对不起,蛋头老兄
Mission accomplished. Well done, men. Pack it up. We're goin' home.
任务完成了,干得好,收工了,我们回去吧
So did I tell ya? Nothin' to worry about.
我就说吧,没什么好担心的
I knew you were right all along, Woody. Never doubted ya for a second.
我早就知道你是对,胡迪,我从来没有怀疑过你
Wait a minute. Oh!
等一下
- What do we have here? - Wait! Turn that thing back on!
- 这是什么啊? - 等一下!再把对讲机打开
Come in Mother Bird! Come in Mother Bird!
大鸟妈妈请回答,大鸟妈妈请回答
Mom has pulled a surprise present from the closet.
妈咪从柜子里拿出礼物
Andy's opening it. He's really ex. Cited about this one.
安弟正在拆,他看到这个礼物很兴奋
- Mom, what is it? - It's a huge package.
- 妈咪,这是什么? - 是个很大的盒子
Oh, get outta the... One of the kids is in the way. I can't see.
等一下,有一个孩子挡住我的视线,我看不见
- It's a... - Wow!
- 那...那是... - 喔!
It's a what? What is it?
那是什么啊?是什么啊?
- Oh, no! - Oh, ya big lizard!
- 惨了 - 你这只蠢蜥蜴
- Now we'll never know what it is! - Way to go, Rex!
- 我们永远不知道那是什么了 - 看你干得好事
No, no! Turn him around! Turn him around!
不对,不对,转过去,转过去
He's puttin' 'em in backwa... Here, you're puttin' 'em in backwards!
不对,不对,放反了,你们把它们放反了
Plus is positive, minus is negative! Oh, let me!
正是阳极,负是阴极,我来吧
Let's go to my room, guys!
到我的房间来玩
Red alert! Red alert! Andy is coming upstairs!
紧急状况,紧急状况,安弟要上楼了
- There! - Juvenile intrusion!
- 搞定了 - 儿童入侵
Repeat resume your positions now!
重复,立刻回到自己岗位上
Andy's coming! Everybody, back to your places! Hurry!
安弟来了,快回到自己的位置上
Get to your places! Get to your places!
快回到自己的位置
Where's my ear? Who's seen my ear? Did you see my ear?
我的耳朵,我的耳朵呢?有谁看到我的耳朵?
Out of my way! Here I come! Here I come!
让开,让开,我来了,我来了
Hey, look, its lasers light up. Take that, Zurg!
你们看,他的雷射亮了,帮我拿一下
Quick, make a space. This is where the spaceship lands.
就摆在这里,这里是太空船降落的地方
And he does it like that. And he does a karate chop action!
他还是空手道高手呢
Come on down, guys! It's time for games! We've got prizes!
小朋友下来吧,玩游戏啰
- what's it - Can you see we've got prizes
- 那是什么东东? - 你看得到吗?
- What the heck is up there? - Woody, who's up there with ya?
- 那上面的东西是什么? - 胡迪,谁跟你在上面啊?
Woody?
胡迪
- What are you doing under the bed? - Nothin'. Nothin'.
- 你在床底下干什么啊? - 没什么,没什么
I'm sure Andy was just a little ex. Cited, that's all.
我想安弟有一点太兴奋了
Too much cake and ice cream, I suppose. It's just a mistake!
大概是吃了太多冰淇淋跟蛋糕,那只是个意外
Well, that mistake is sitting in your spot, Woody.
那个意外,正坐在你的地盘上,胡迪
- Have you been replaced? - What did I tell you earlier?
- 你被人取代了吗? - 我刚刚是怎么告诉你的?
No one is getting replaced.
没有人可以取代我们
Now, let's all be polite and give whatever it is up there
好了,不管那上面是什么,我们都要给他来一个...
a nice, big Andy's- room welcome.
礼貌的热情的,安弟房间式的欢迎
(太空骑警巴斯光年雷射)
Buzz Lightyear to Star Command.
巴斯光年呼叫星际总部
Come in, Star Command.
收到了请回答
Star Command, come in. Do you read me?
星际总部,请回答,你们有没有收到?
Why don't they answer? My ship!
他们为什么不回答?我的太空船
(巴斯光年)
Blast! This'll take weeks to repair.
糟糕,要花好久才能修好
Buzz Lightyear mission log, stardate 4- 0- 7- 2.
巴斯光年任务日志,星际日期4072年
My ship has run off course en route to sector 12.
我的太空船,在第十二区脱离轨道
I've crash- landed on a strange planet.
我坠落在一个奇怪的星球
The impact must've awoken me from hypersleep.
我一定是被,巨大的撞击惊醒
Terrain seems a bit unstable.
这里的地形似乎有点不稳定
No readout yet if the air is breathable.
目前还没有,能不能呼吸空气的读数
And there seems to be no sign of intelligent life anywhere.
而且也看不出来,有智慧型生命的迹象
Hello!
你好
Whoa! Hey! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
站住
Did I frighten you? Didn't mean to.
我吓到你了吗?我不是故意的
Sorry. Howdy. My name is Woody.
抱歉,你好,我叫胡迪
And this is Andy's room. That's all I wanted to say.
而这里呢,是安弟的房间,请恕我直言
And also, there has been a bit of a mix-up.
你一定是搞错了
This is my spot, see, the bed here.
这是我的地盘,而这张床...
Local law enforcement. It's about time you got here.
当地的执法人员,你早该来了
I'm Buzz Lightyear, Space Ranger, Universe Protection Unit.
我是巴斯光年,保护宇宙小组的太空骑警
My ship has crash- landed here by mistake.
我的太空船意外坠机了
Yes, it is a mistake because, you see, the bed here is my spot.
是呀,这是一个意外,因为这张床是我的地盘
I need to repair my turbo boosters.
我要修理我的涡轮推进器
Do you people still use fossil fuel, or have you discovered crystallic fusion?
你们现在是用旧燃料,还是已经有结晶体溶解物
Well, let's see. We got double- A's.
我想想...我们有三号电池
Watch yourself! Halt! Who goes there?
小心,站住,什么人?
Don't shoot! It's okay. Friends.
别开枪,没事,是朋友
- Do you know these life- forms? - Yes! They're Andy's toys.
- 你认识这些生物吗? - 认识,他们是安弟的玩具
All right, everyone, you're clear to come up.
好了,你们可以上来了
I am Buzz Lightyear. I come in peace.
我是巴斯光年,和平使者
Oh, I'm so glad you're not a dinosaur!
我好高兴,你不是恐龙
Wh- why, thank you!
谢谢
Now, thank you all for your kind welcome!
谢谢你们热情的欢迎
- Say, what's that button do? - I'll show you.
- 那个按钮是干什么的? - 我来示范
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
巴斯光年拯救宇宙
Hey, Woody's got something like that. His is a pull string.
胡迪也有那样的东西,他的是拉线的
- Only it's... - Only it sounds like a car ran over it.
- 只是... - 只是听起来像被车子,压过
Oh, yeah, but not like this. This is a quality sound system.
对,不像这个,这个是高品质声音系统
Probably all copper wiring, huh?
配线可能是铜线哦
So, where you from? Singapore? Hong Kong?
对了,你从哪里来的?新加坡?香港?
Well, no. Actually, I'm stationed up in the Gamma Quadrant of Sector Four.
不,事实上我是驻扎在,第四区域的伽玛象限
As a member of the elite Universe Protection Unit
我是宇宙保护小组
of the Space Ranger Corps,
太空警备队的队员
I protect the galaxy from the threat of invasion
我保护我们的星际,免于受到札克天王的入侵
from the evil Emperor Zurg, sworn enemy of the Galactic Alliance.
Oh, really? I'm from Playskool.
是吗?我来自儿乐宝
And I'm from Mattel. Well, I'm not really from Mattel.
而我来自美泰儿,其实我并不是来自美泰儿
I'm actually from a smaller company that was purchased in a leveraged buyout.
我是来自比较小的公司,结果被美泰儿收购了,我想...
You'd think they'd never seen a new toy before.
一群土包子,没看过新玩具
Well, sure. Look at him. He's got more gadgets on him than a Swiss Army knife.
是,你看看他身上的小东西,比瑞士刀还要多呢
Please be careful.
小心点
You don't want to be in the way when my laser goes off.
被我的雷射击中可不是好玩的,嘿,雷射?
Hey, a laser! How come you don't have a laser, Woody?
你怎么会没有雷射呢?胡迪
It's not a laser! It's a... It's a little light bulb that blinks.
那不是雷射,那只是会闪的灯泡
- What's with him? - Laser envy.
- 他怎么了? - 嫉妒雷射
All right, that's enough!
好了,夠了
Look, we're all very impressed with Andy's new toy.
我们对安弟的新玩具,都印象深刻
- Toy? - T- O- Y. Toy!
- 玩具 - TOY玩具
Ex. Cuse me, I think the word you're searching for is "Space Ranger."
对不起,我想你用的字应该是太空骑警
The word I'm searching for I can't say because there's preschool toys present.
我想要用的字现在不能说,因为有学龄前的玩具在场
Gettin' kinda tense, aren't ya?
你有点紧张了吧?
Mr. Lightyear, now, I'm curious.
巴斯先生,我很好奇
What does a Space Ranger actually do?
一个太空骑警都做些什么呢?
He's not a Space Ranger!
他不是太空骑警
He doesn't fight evil or, or shoot lasers or fly!
他不会打击邪恶,发射雷射,也不会飞
Ex. Cuse me.
打个岔
Oh, impressive wingspan! Very good!
好赞的机翼哦,酷毙了
Oh, what? What? These are plastic. He can't fly!
拜托,什么嘛?这些是塑胶,他才不会飞
They are a terillium- carbonic alloy, and I can fly.
这是碳化合金,而且我的确会飞
- No, you can't. - Yes, I can.
- 不,你不会 - 会,我会
- You can't. - Can.
- 你不会 - 会
Can't. Can't. Can't!
不会,不会,不会
I tell you, I could fly around this room with my eyes closed!
就算我闭着眼睛,也可以飞遍整个房间
- Okay, then, Mr. Light Beer, prove it. - All right, then, I will.
- 好啊,泡泡头先生,证明吧 - 那好吧
Stand back, everyone!
各位请退后
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇宙浩瀚无垠
- Can! - Whoa!
- 我会飞 - 哇!
Oh, wow, you flew magnificently!
你飞得有夠炫的
- I found my movin' buddy. - Thank you. Thank you all. Thank you.
- 我找到搬家伙伴了 - 谢谢,谢谢你们,谢谢
That wasn't flying! That was... falling with style.
那不叫飞行,那只是摔得很好看
Man, the dolls must really go for you. Can you teach me that?
小妞们一定迷死你了,教教我好吗?
- Golly bob howdy! - Oh, shut up!
- 刚刚那一招真是太酷了 - 闭嘴
You know, in a couple of days,
再过几天
everything will be just the way it was. They'll see.
这里就会恢复老样子了,等着瞧吧
They'll see.
不信你们看
I'm still Andy's favorite toy.
我还是安弟最爱的玩具,我还是安弟最爱的玩具
∮ I was on top of the world livin' high ∮
∮ 我现在高高在上 ∮
∮ It was right in my pocket ∮
∮ 样样事都享受现成 ∮
(ABC牛仔竞技秀)
∮ I was livin' the life ∮
∮ 我现在的光景 ∮
∮ Things were just the way they should be ∮
∮ 想要什么都行 ∮
∮ When from out of the sky like a bomb ∮
∮ 忽然间从天外飞过来 ∮
∮ Comes some little punk in a rocket ∮
∮ 一颗要爆发的炸弹 ∮
∮ Now all of a sudden some strange things are happening to me ∮
∮ 从此我发现,一些奇怪的事要发生 ∮
Buzz Lightyear to the rescue!
巴斯光年拯救宇宙
∮ Strange ∮
∮ 奇怪的... ∮
(我要你加入太空骑警)
∮ Things are happening to me ∮
∮ 事情发生在我身上 ∮
(飞向宇宙浩瀚无垠)
∮ Strange ∮
∮ 事情... ∮
∮ Things ∮
∮ 真奇怪 ∮
(飞向宇宙浩瀚无垠)
∮ Strange things are happening to me ∮
∮ 奇怪的事情发生在我身上 ∮
∮ Ain't no doubt about it ∮
∮ 这是毫无疑问的 ∮
(巴斯)
∮ I had friends I had lots of friends ∮
∮ 我曾拥有许多朋友 ∮
∮ Now all my friends are gone ∮
∮ 现在一个也不剩 ∮
∮ And I'm doin' the best I can ∮
∮ 我叫他们 ∮
∮ To carry on ∮
∮ 他们对我是冷冰冰的 ∮
∮ I had power ∮
∮ 我曾有特权 ∮
∮ I was respected ∮
∮ 我曾被重视 ∮
∮ But not any more ∮
∮ 但好景不常 ∮
∮ And I've lost the love of the one ∮
∮ 我失去我最喜欢的人... ∮
∮ Whom I adore ∮
∮ 的关爱 ∮
∮ Let me tell you 'bout it Strange ∮
∮ 让我告诉你 ∮
∮ Things are happenin' to me ∮
∮ 奇怪的事发生在我身上 ∮
∮ Strange ∮
∮ 奇怪... ∮
∮ Things ∮
∮ 的事情 ∮
∮ Strange ∮
∮ 奇怪... ∮
∮ Things are happenin' to me ∮
∮ 奇怪的事发生在我身上 ∮
∮ Ain't no doubt about it ∮
∮ 这是毫无疑问的 ∮
∮ Strange ∮
∮ 奇怪... ∮
∮ Things ∮
∮ 的事情 ∮
∮ Strange ∮
∮ 奇怪... ∮
∮ Things ∮
∮ 的事情 ∮
Finally!
终于重见天日了
Hey, who's got my hat?
我的帽子在哪里啊?
Look, I'm Woody! Howdy, howdy, howdy!
大家好,我是胡迪,大家好,大家好
Gimme that!
还给我
Say there, Lizard and Stretchy Dog, let me show you something.
抱抱龙,弹簧狗,我给你们看样东西
It looks as though I've been accepted into your culture.
我好像被你们给同化了
Your chief, Andy, inscribed his name on me.
你们老大安弟,把他的名字刻在我身上
Wow!
哇赛
With permanent ink too!
还用奇异笔耶
Well, I must get back to repairing my ship.
好了,我要回去修我的太空船了
Don't let it get to you, Woody.
胡迪,不要让他影乡到你
Let what? I don't... What do you mean? Who?
你说什么?什么意思?谁?
I know Andy's ex. Cited about Buzz.
我知道安弟很喜欢巴斯
But you know he'll always have a special place for you.
但是你在他的心目当中,一直占有一席之地的
- Yeah, like the attic. - All right, that's it!
- 是啊,是块畸零地 - 好了,我受夠了
Unidirectional bonding strip.
单向的细长连结带
Mr. Lightyear wants more tape.
巴斯先生要胶带
Listen, Light Snack, you stay away from Andy.
听着,泡泡头,你最好离安弟远一点
He's mine, and no one is taking him away from me.
他是我的,没有人可以拆散他跟我
What are you talking about?
你到底在说什么啊?
Where's that bonding strip?
我的连结带呢?
And another thing:
还有一件事
Stop with this spaceman thing! It's getting on my nerves!
从现在开始,少再说什么太空的事,那快把我逼疯了
Are you saying you wanna lodge a complaint with Star Command?
不高兴可以向,星际总部申诉啊
Okay! Well, so you wanna do it the hard way, huh?
好,我看你是,敬酒不吃吃罚酒
- Don't even think about it, cowboy. - Oh, yeah, tough guy?
- 警长,不要无理取闹 - 是吗?硬汉
The air isn't... tox. Ic.
这里的空气没有毒嘛
How dare you open a spaceman's helmet on an uncharted planet!
你怎么可以在一个,不知名的星球上打开我的头盔
My eyeballs could've been sucked from their sockets!
我的眼球很可能被吸出去的
You actually think you're the Buzz Lightyear?
你真的以为...你就是太空人巴斯光年吗?
Oh, all this time I thought it was an act!
我一直以为你只是装模作样
Hey, guys, look! It's the real Buzz Lightyear!
各位,快来看,他是真的巴斯光年
You're mocking me, aren't you?
你在讽刺我,对吧?
Oh, no, no. No, no, no, no, no. Buzz, look, an alien!
不是啦...巴斯,有外星人
Where?
哪里?
Ha ha ha!
哈哈哈...
Yes!
好耶
It's Sid!
是阿薛
Don't move!
不准动
I thought he was at summer camp.
我还以为他去夏令营呢
They must've kicked him out early this year.
他一定是被踢出来了
Oh, no, not Sid!
天哪,怎么又是他营
Incoming!
炮弹来袭!
- Who is it this time? - I... I can't... I can't tell.
- 这回又是谁啊营 - 我...我看不清楚是谁
- Hey, where's Lenny? - Right here, Woody.
- 雷尼呢? - 我在这儿,胡迪
Oh, no, I can't bear to watch one of these again.
不,我受不了残忍的画面
Oh, no, it's a Combat Carl.
天哪!是战斗兵卡卡'而
What's going on?
怎么回事啊?
Nothing that concerns you spacemen, just us toys.
这不关你们太空人的事,是我们玩具自己的事
I'd better take a look anyway.
最好让我看一看
Why is that soldier strapped to an ex. Plosive device?
那个阿兵哥,为什么绑着爆炸装置?
That's why: Sid.
因为那个...阿薛
Sure is a hairy fellow.
他的毛还真多
No, no, that's Scud, you idiot.
不是,那是阿德,白痴
That is Sid.
他才是阿薛
- You mean that happy child? - That ain't no happy child.
- 那个天真的小孩? - 他才不天真呢
He tortures toys, just for fun!
折磨那些玩具是他的最爱
Well, then we've got to do something.
我看我们必须想个办法
What are you doing? Get down from there!
你在干什么?快下来
- I'm gonna teach that boy a lesson. - Yeah, sure. You go ahead.
- 我要给那孩子一个教训 - 是啊,好,尽管去
Melt him with your scary laser.
用你吓人的雷射溶化他
Be careful with that! It's extremely dangerous.
小心,别乱碰,那是非常危险的
He's lighting it! He's lighting it! Hit the dirt!
点火了,他点火了
Look out!
趴下来
Yes! He's gone! He's history!
好耶,死了,他死了
I could've stopped him.
我本来可以阻止他
Buzz, I would love to see you try.
巴斯,我很想看看你的本事
Of course, I'd love to see you as a crater.
我更想看看,你要怎么去当烈士
The sooner we move, the better.
真希望立刻就能搬家
Yeah!
好耶!
(待售梦幻房地产  出售)
To infinity and beyond!
飞向浩瀚宇宙
All this packing makes me hungry.
打包完了肚子好饿哦
What would you say to dinner at, oh, Pizza Planet?
我们的晚餐就去...比萨星球吧
Pizza Planet? Oh, cool!
比萨星球!哦酷
Go wash your hands, and I'll get Molly ready.
去洗手,我替茉莉换衣服
- Can I bring some toys? - You can bring one toy.
- 我可以带玩具去吗? - 你只能带一个玩具
- Just one? - One toy?
- 只能带一个啊 - 一个玩具
Will Andy pick me?
安弟会选我吗?
(别作梦)
"Don't count on it"?
别作梦,不是吧?
Buzz! Oh, Buzz! Buzz Lightyear.
巴斯,巴斯,巴斯光年
Buzz Lightyear, thank goodness. We've got trouble!
巴斯光年,老天爷,我们有麻烦了
- Trouble? Where? - Down there. Just down there.
- 麻烦,在哪儿? - 下面,就在下面!
A helpless toy, it's... it's trapped, Buzz!
一个无助的玩具,它被困住了
Then we've no time to lose.
我立刻去看看
I don't see anything!
什么都没有耶
Oh, he's there! Just, just keep looking!
就在那下面,再找找
What kind of toy...
他长什么样子...
Buzz!
巴斯
I don't see him in the driveway.
他没有摔在车道上耶
- I think he bounced into Sid's yard! - Oh! Buzz!
- 我猜他弹到阿薛的院子了 - 巴斯
Hey, everyone, R.C.'s trying to say something. What is it, boy?
各位,遥控车好像有话要说,什么事,老弟?
- He's saying that this was no accident. - What do you mean?
- 他是说这件事情并不是意外 - 什么意思?
- I mean Humpty- Dumpty was pushed... - No!
- 巴斯是被推出去的 - 不是吧?
...by Woody!
是胡迪推的
- What? - Wait a minute.
- 什么? - 等一下
You don't think I meant to knock Buzz out the window, do you?
你...你不会以为我是故意,把巴斯推出窗外吧?
Potato Head?
是吧,蛋头?
That's Mr. Potato Head to you, you back- stabbing murderer!
你该叫我蛋头先生,你这暗箭伤人的凶手
Now, it was an accident, guys.
那是个意外
Come on. Now, you, you gotta believe me.
各位,拜托你们...你们一定要相信我
We believe ya, Woody. Right, Rex?
我们相信你,胡迪,对吧,抱抱龙?
Well, ye... N... I don't like confrontations!
这个...我不喜欢跟人家对质
Where is your honor, dirt bag? You are an absolute disgrace!
你的荣誉到哪儿去了?你真的是军人的一大耻辱
You don't deserve to... Hey!
你根本不配对我们发号施令
You couldn't handle Buzz cutting in on your playtime, could you, Woody?
受不了巴斯光年占去你的时间,对吧,胡迪
Didn't wanna face the fact that Buzz just might be Andy's new favorite toy.
你无法面对巴斯可能成为,安弟最喜欢的玩具这件事实
So you got rid of him.
所以你想要除掉他
Well, what if Andy starts playing with me more, Woody, huh?
如果安弟花很多时间和我玩呢
You gonna knock me outta the window too?
你也要把我丢到窗外吗?
I don't think we should give him the chance.
我们不能让他胡作非为
There he is, men. Frag him!
他在那里,丢手榴弹
Let's string him up by his pull string!
用他的拉绳把他绑起来
- I got dibs on his hat! - Would you boys stop it!
- 我要他的帽子 - 你们快住手好吗?
Tackle him!
抓住他
No, no, no! Wait! I can ex. Plain everything!
不...等等...我可以解释,安弟,快点
Okay, Mom, be right down. I've gotta get Buzz.
好,我马上就来,我要去拿巴斯
Retreat!
撤退
Mom, do you know where Buzz is?
妈咪,你有没有看到巴斯?
No, I haven't seen him.
没有,我没有看到
- Andy, I'm heading out the door! - But, Mom, I can't find him!
- 安弟,我要出门啰 - 但是我找不到他
Honey, just grab some other toy. Now, come on!
儿子,先拿别的玩具,快走了
Oh, okay.
好吧
I couldn't find my Buzz. I know I left him right there.
我找不到巴斯,我明明放在桌上的
Honey, I'm sure he's around. You'll find him.
乖乖,他一定还在那儿,你会找到他的
It's too short! We need more monkeys!
太短了,我们还需要连环猴
There aren't any more! That's the whole barrel!
已经没有了!整桶都倒光了
Buzz, the monkeys aren't working!
巴斯,这些连环猴不夠
We're formulating another plan! Stay calm!
我们会再想其他的办法的,保持冷静
Oh, where could he be?
他到底在哪里啊?
(恐龙加油站)
(汽油)
- Can I help pump the gas? - Sure! I'll even let you drive.
- 我来帮忙加油 - 好啊,我还能让你开车呢
- Yeah? - Yeah, when you're 16.
- 真的吗? - 对,等你满十六岁
Funny, Mom.
真讨厌,妈咪又在骗人家
Great. How am I gonna convince those guys it was an accident?
天啊!我要怎么说服那些傢伙,那只是个意外
Buzz!
巴斯
Buzz! Ha! You're alive!
巴斯!你还活着
This is great! Oh, I'm saved! I'm saved.
太棒了,我有救了!我有救了!
Andy'll find you here, he'll take us back to the room
安弟会发现你,他会带我们两个回房间
and then you can tell everyone that this was all just a big mistake.
然后你就可以告诉每一个人,这只是一个天大的误会
Huh? Right? Buddy?
对吧?伙伴
I just want you to know that even though you tried to terminate me,
我只是要让你知道,虽然你一直想要毁灭我
revenge is not an idea we promote on my planet.
但是在我们的星球,并不鼓励我们复仇
- Oh. Well, that's good. - But we're not on my planet, are we?
- 那很好 - 但这里不是我的星球,对吧?
No.
对
Okay, come on!
好,你来啊
You want a piece of me?
你想要拆了我吗?
Buzz Buzz Buzz Lightyear to the rescue.
巴...巴斯光年拯救宇宙
- Next stop. - Pizza Planet! Yeah!
- 下一站 - 比萨星球,好耶
Andy
安弟
Wh... Doesn't he realize that I'm not there?
他不知道我不在车上吗?
I'm lost!
啊,我被遗弃了
Oh, I'm a lost toy!
我是个没人要的玩具
Buzz Lightyear mission log.
巴斯光年任务日志
The local sheriff and I seem to be at a huge refueling station of some sort.
警长跟我似乎在一个,很巨大的燃料补给站
You!
你...
- According to my navi- computer, the... - Shut up!
- 根据我的导航电脑... - 闭嘴
- Just shut up, you idiot! - Sheriff, this is no time to panic.
- 给我闭嘴,白痴 - 警长,现在没有时间惊慌
This is the perfect time to panic. I'm lost. Andy is gone.
现在是惊慌的好时机,我被遗弃了,安弟走了
They're gonna move from their house in two days, and it's all your fault!
他们再过两天就要搬家了,这全是你的错
My... My fault? If you hadn't pushed me out of the window in the first place...
我...我的错,如果你一开始,没有把我推出窗外...
Oh, yeah?
是吗?
Well, if you hadn't shown up in your stupid little cardboard spaceship
对,如果不是你,坐着那艘笨太空船出现
and taken away everything that was important to me...
并且抢走,原来属于我的东西的话...
Don't talk to me about importance!
你不能怪到我身上
Because of you the security of this entire universe is in jeopardy!
就是因为你,使整个宇宙的安全受到危险
What? What are you talkin' about?
什么?你在说什么啊?
Right now, poised at the edge of the galaxy, Emperor Zurg
就是现在,札克天王在银河系边缘
has been secretly building a weapon
秘密建立了一种武器
with the destructive capacity to annihilate an entire planet!
那个玩意儿,足以毁灭整个星球
I alone have information that reveals this weapon's only weakness.
只有我有资料,可以击破这武器唯一的弱点
And you, my friend, are responsible
而你,朋友
for delaying my rendezvous with Star Command!
就是你耽误了,我跟星际总部会合的时间
You... are... a... toy!
你是个玩具!
You aren't the real Buzz Lightyear! You're a...
你不是真的巴斯光年!
You're an action figure! You are a child's plaything!
你...只是个会动的玩具,只是给小朋友玩的玩具
You are a sad, strange little man, and you have my pity.
你是个可悲又奇怪的人,我很同情你
Farewell.
再见了
Oh, yeah? Well, good riddance, ya loony!
是吗?走啊,疯子
"Rendezvous with Star Command."
跟星际总部会合个头啦
- Hey, gas dude! - You talkin' to me?
- 加油小弟 - 你在叫我吗?
- Yeah, man. Can you help me? - Pizza Planet? Andy!
- 没错,你能帮我吗? - 比萨星球?安弟
Do you know where Cutting Boulevard is?
你知道卡廷大道在哪里吗?
Oh, no!
不
I can't show my face in that room without Buzz.
没有巴斯我没有脸回去
- Buzz! Buzz, come back! - Go away!
- 巴斯,巴斯,快回来 - 走开
No! Buzz, you gotta come back! I...
巴斯,你一定要回来
(比萨星球)
I found a spaceship!
我找到一艘太空船了
It's a spaceship, Buzz!
一艘太空船,巴斯
Come on, man, hurry up! Like, the pizzas are getting cold here!
老兄,快一点,这些比萨会凉掉
- Cutting Boulevard, huh? - Yeah, yeah. Which way?
- 卡廷大道? - 对,在哪里?
Now, you're sure this space freighter will return to its port of origin
好,你确定这个太空运输机,送完了货物之后
once it jettisons its food supply?
就会回到原来太空站吗?
And when we get there, we'll be able to find a way to transport you home.
等到了那里以后,我们再来想个办法送你回家
- Well, then, let's climb aboard. - No, no, no, wait, Buzz! Buzz!
- 好,那我们上船吧 - 等等...巴斯
Let's get in the back. No one will see us there.
我们到车后面,那里不会被人发现
Negative. There are no restraining harnesses in the cargo area.
不行,货舱里没有安全设备,那是载货的
- We'll be much safer in the cockpit. - Yeah, bu...
- 在机舱里比较安全 - 对,但是...
Buzz! Buzz!
巴斯!巴斯!
That's two lefts and a right, huh?
先左转两次,然后再右转,对吧?
- Thanks for the directions, okay? - Yeah. And remember, kid...
- 谢谢你的帮忙,谢了 - 嗯,记住它,孩子
Buzz!
巴斯
It's safer in the cockpit than the cargo bay. What an idiot.
在机舱比在货舱里安全,真是白痴
(比萨星球)
Net shuttle lift- off is scheduled for
下一班前往比萨星球的,高速接驳专车
T- minus 30 minutes and counting.
正在倒数计时中
You are clear to enter.
你可以进去了
Welcome to Pizza Planet.
欢迎来到比萨星球
(开启舱门)
The white zone is for immediate pizza...
白色区域是快速比萨外带区...
Sheriff!
警长
There you are.
警长?你在这儿呀
Now, the entrance is heavily guarded. We need a way to get inside.
入口守备很森严,我们必须想办法进去
Great idea, Woody.
好主意,胡迪
I like your thinkin'.
我喜欢你的点子
You are clear to enter. Welcome to Pizza Planet.
你可以进去了,欢迎来到比萨星球
Now!
走吧
Quickly, Sheriff! The air lock is closing.
快点,舱门就要关了
Jones party of five your shuttle is now boarding...
琼斯一家人,一共五个人,你的接驳车正在发射台十二号
Hey, Mom, can we have some tokens?
妈,我们可以去换代币吗?
Watch where you're going!
噢,走路小心点
Sorry.
抱歉
Ten nine eight seven six...
十,九,八,七,六...
five four three...
五,四,三...
two one.
二,一
What a spaceport! Good work, Woody.
好棒的太空船哦,干得好,胡迪
(星球杀手)
(外星怪物)
(棒打外星人)
Mom, can I play Black Hole? Please, please, please?
妈咪,我能玩黑洞吗?拜托...
- Andy! - Now, we need to find a ship
- 安弟! - 我们要去找一艘
- that's headed for Sector 12. - Wait a minute. No, Buzz! This way.
- 到十二区的太空船 - 等一下,巴斯,往这边
- There's a special ship. I just saw it. - You mean it has hyperdrive?
- 那边有一艘特别的船 - 它有超高动力吗?
Hyperactive hyperdrive.
超高的启动动力
And Astro... turf!
还有太空...驱动
- Where is it? I don't see the... - Come on. That's it.
- 在哪里?我没有看到... - 这,这
Spaceship!
太空船!
(钓娃娃准备发射台)
All right, Buzz, get ready. And...
好了,巴斯,准备了
- And the universe ex. Plodes! - Okay, Buzz, when I say go,
- 就快要好了 - 等我一说"上"
we're gonna jump in the basket. Buzz!
我们就跳到篮子里,巴斯
(奖品)
- No! - Mom, if I eat all my pizza,
- 不好了 - 妈,如果我把比萨都吃光
can I have some alien slime?
你能不能给我外星黏液?
This cannot be happening to me.
我怎么会碰上这种事
- A stranger. - From the outside.
- 陌生人 - 他来自外面
Greetings. I am Buzz Lightyear.
你们好!我是巴斯光年
I come in peace.
和平的使者
Before your space journey re- energize yourself
在你今天离开前
with a slice of pepperoni now boarding at counter three.
请用一片腊肠比萨补充能源,现在请从三号柜台登机
This is an intergalactic emergency.
这是星际紧急事件
I need to commandeer your vessel to Sector 12.
我要征召你们的船到第十二区
Who's in charge here?
这里谁负责?
The claw!
是爪子
The claw is our master.
爪子是我们的主人
The claw chooses who will go and who will stay.
爪子会选择谁留下来谁离开
- This is ludicrous. - Hey, bozo, you got a brain in there?
- 这太荒谬了 - 过份,这什么烂机器嘛?
Take that!
可恶,欠扁
Oh, no! Sid!
糟了,阿薛
Get down!
快趴下来
(任务指挥中心)
What's gotten into you? I was...
警长,你怎么了,我...
You are the one that decided to climb into this...
是你自己决定爬上来的
The claw, it moves.
爪子!它动了
I have been chosen!
我被选中了
Farewell, my friends. I go on to a better place.
再见了,我的朋友,我要去更好玩的地方了
Gotcha!
抓到了
A Buzz Lightyear? No way!
巴斯光年,不可能
Yes!
好耶
Buzz! No!
巴斯,不!
Hey!
嘿!
He has been chosen!
他被选中了
- He must go. - Hey!
- 他一定得走 - 嘿!
- What are you doing? - Do not fight the claw.
- 不要触怒爪子 - 你们在干什么?
Stop it! Stop it, you zealots!
放手,放手!你们这些疯子
All right! Double prizes!
棒呆了!双重大奖!
Let's go home and... play.
我们回家去玩吧
Sheriff, I can see your dwelling from here.
警长,我看到你家了
- You're almost home. - Nirvana is coming.
- 你就快到家了 - 神秘之门快到了
- The mystic portal awaits. - Will you be quiet?
- 通往极乐世界 - 拜托你闭嘴
You guys don't get it, do you?
你们两个根本不懂
Once we go into Sid's house, we won't be coming out.
只要进了阿薛家,一辈子都别想出来
Whoa, Scud! Hey, boy!
阿德,好乖
Sit! Good boy.
坐下来,好乖
- Hey, I got something for you, boy. - Freeze!
- 我有东西要给你 - 不要动
Ready, set, now!
预备,咬!
Hannah! Hey, Hannah!
汉娜!汉娜!
- What? - Did I get my package in the mail?
- 干嘛? - 你有没有看到我的包裹?
- I don't know. - What do you mean you don't know?
- 我不知道 - 你不知道是什么意思?
I don't know!
我不知道
- Oh, no, Hannah! Look, janie! - What? Hey!
- 糟了,汉娜,你看珍妮 - 干嘛?
- She's sick! - No, she's not!
- 她病了 - 她才没有
I'll have to perform one of my operations.
我要马上帮她动个手术
- No! - No, not Sid's room. Not there.
- 阿薛,把她还给我 - 不,不要进阿薛的房间
Hey, give her back!
阿薛,把她还给我
Sid! Sid!
阿薛!阿薛!
Oh, no, we have a sick patient here, nurse.
护士,我们这里有一个病辜
Prepare the OR, stat!
准备动手术,快点
Patient is... prepped.
病人准备好啰
No one's ever attempted a double bypass brain transplant before.
以前从来没有人,动过脑袋移植的手术
Now for the tricky part. Pliers!
这种手术很困难,钳子
I don't believe that man's ever been to medical school.
我想那个孩子,应该没有上过医学院吧
Doctor, you've done it!
医生,你成功了
(我超爱爆裂物)
Hannah!
汉娜
Janie's all better now.
珍妮现在好多了
- Mom! Mom! - She's lying!
- 妈,阿薛弄坏我的娃娃 - 她说谎
Whatever she says, it's not true!
不管她说什么都不是真的
(死灵石怪)
(杀手保罗)
We are gonna die. I'm outta here!
我们死定了,我要离开
Locked.
锁住了
There's gotta be another way outta here.
一定还有别的出口
Buzz? Was that you?
巴斯,那是你吗?
Hey, hi there, little fella.
你好,小傢伙
Come out here. Do you know a way outta here?
出来啊!你知道出去的路吗?
Buzz!
巴...巴斯!
They're cannibals.
他们会自相残杀
Mayday, mayday.
求救,求救
Come in, Star Command. Send reinforcements.
星际总部请回答,请派后援部队
Star Command, do you copy?
星际总部,收到吗?
I've set my laser from stun to kill.
我的雷射枪,最大威力可以杀人
Great. Great. Yeah, and if anyone attacks us, we can blink 'em to death.
好极了,如果有人攻击的话,你可以闪灯把他们闪死
Hey, you guys, I think I found him!
各位,我找到他了
Buzz, is that you?
巴斯,是你吗?
Whiskers, will you get outta here!
咪咪,拜托你走开好吗?
You're interfering with the search and rescue!
你千扰到我们的搜救任务了
Look, they're home.
你们看,他们回来了
Mom, have you seen Woody?
妈咪,你看到胡迪没有?
- Where was the last place you left him? - Right here in the van.
- 你最后把他放在哪儿? - 就在车上啊
Oh, I'm sure he's there. You're just not looking hard enough.
他一定在的,只是你没好好找而已
He's not here, Mom. Woody's gone.
他不在车上,胡迪不见了
Woody's gone?
胡迪不见了?
Yeah, boy, the weasel ran away.
真是的,那黄鼠狼逃走了
Huh? Huh? I told you he was guilty.
我早说他有罪
Who would've thought he was capable of such atrocities?
谁也没有想到,他会做出这么可怕的事情
Oh, Slink, I hope he's okay.
弹簧狗,我希望他没事
Oh, a survivor. Where's the rebel base? Talk!
有生还者,叛军的基地在哪儿,说!
I can see your will is strong.
你的意志力很坚强嘛
Well, we have ways of making you talk.
不过我们有很多办法,让你乖乖招供
Where are your rebel friends now?
你的叛军朋友在哪里?
Sid, your Pop Tarts are ready!
阿薛,你的点心好了
All right!
好耶
Are you all right? I'm proud of you, Sheriff.
你还好吗?我真以你为荣
A lesser man would've talked under such torture.
一般人被这样折磨早就招了
I sure hope this isn't permanent.
希望不会留下疤痕
Still no word from Star Command. We're not that far from the space port.
还是没有星际总部的消息,我们离太空站不远了
The door. It's open! We're free!
那扇门...没关好,我们自由了
- Woody, we don't know what's out there! - I'll tell you wha...
- 胡迪,我们不知道外面有什么 - 我会告诉你...
They're gonna eat us, Buzz! Do something quick!
他们要吃我们,巴斯,快想办法
Shield your eyes.
遮住眼睛
It's not working. I recharged it before I left. It should be good for...
奇怪了,我离开前才充的电,应该能发射...
You idiot! You're a toy! Use your karate chop action!
你这个白痴,你只是个玩具,用你的空手道打他们
- Get away! - Hey! Hey! How're you doin' that?
- 走开 - 你在干什么?
- Stop that. - Back! Back, you savages! Back!
- 停下 - 退后,野蛮人让开
- Woody, stop it! - Sorry, guys, but dinner's canceled!
- 胡迪,放手 - 抱歉,各位,不陪你们玩了
There's no place like home! There's no place like home!
我们可以回家了,我们可以回家了
There's no place like home.
我们可以回家了
Another stunt like that, cowboy, you're gonna get us killed.
你再搞这种把戏会害死我们
Don't tell me what to do.
我不用你来教我该怎么做
Yee-haw! Giddyap pardner!
快点,伙伴
We got to get this wagon train a- movin'!
我们得让这火车启动了
Split up!
快分散开来
Calling Buzz Lightyear. Come in Buzz Lightyear.
呼叫巴斯光年,巴斯光年请回答
This is Star Command.
这里是星际总部
- Star Command! - Buzz Lightyear responding. Read you loud and clear.
- 星际总部 - 巴斯光年,你收到吗?
Buzz Lightyear planet Earth needs your help.
巴斯光年,目前地球需要你的帮忙
- On the way! - Buzz Lightyear!
- 出动了 - 巴斯光年
The world's greatest superhero! Now the world's greatest toy!
全世界最棒的超级英雄,现在是全世界最棒的玩具
Buzz has it all! Locking wrist communicator!
巴斯应有尽有,手腕锁定通讯器
- Calling Buzz Lightyear! - Karate chop action!
- 呼叫巴斯光年 - 还会空手道
- Wow! - Pulsating laser light!
- 哇! - 超强雷射光束
- Total annihilation! - Multi- phase voice simulator!
- 彻底的消灭 - 多段式声音模拟器
There's a secret mission in uncharted space.
在一个未知的宇宙,有秘密任务
And best of all high pressure space wings!
还有最酷的高速飞翼
- To infinity and beyond! - Not a flying toy.
- 飞向宇宙浩瀚无垠 - 不是飞行玩具
Get your Buzz Lightyear action figure
拥有巴斯光年
- and save a galay near you! - Buzz Lightyear!
- 你就能拯救邻近的星际 - 巴斯光年
Available at all Al's Toy Barn outlets in the tri- county area.
艾卡而玩具,各大百货公司均有出售
(台湾制造)
∮ Out among the stars I sit ∮
∮ 月亮伴着我航行 ∮
∮ Way beyond the moon ∮
∮ 穿越过星星 ∮
∮ In my silver ship I sailed ∮
∮ 乘着银色的小船 ∮
∮ To a dream that ended too soon ∮
∮ 在那短暂的梦境 ∮
∮ Now I know eactly ∮
∮ 我现在知道自己是谁 ∮
∮ Who I am and what I'm here for ∮
∮ 我能说得尽 ∮
∮ You are a toy! You can't fly! ∮
∮ 你是玩具,你不会飞 ∮
∮ And I will go sailing ∮
∮ 我在记忆里航行 ∮
∮ No more ∮
∮ 哦不 ∮
∮ But no it can't be true ∮
∮ 不是这样 ∮
∮ I could fly if I wanted to ∮
∮ 我能飞,假如我愿意 ∮
∮ Like a bird in the sky ∮
∮ 想像鸟在天空 ∮
∮ If I believed I could fly ∮
∮ 自由的去飞翔 ∮
∮ Why I'd fly ∮
∮ 去飞翔 ∮
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇宙浩瀚无垠
∮ Clearly I ∮
∮ 我 ∮
∮ Will go sailing ∮
∮ 不能再去... ∮
∮ No more ∮
∮ 航行 ∮
Mom! Mom, have you seen my Sally doll?
妈,你有没有看到我的莎莉娃娃?
What, dear? What was that?
什么?你说什么?
Never mind!
没事了啦
Buzz, the coast is clear. Buzz, where are you?
巴斯,安全了吗?巴斯,你在哪里?
There's a secret mission in uncharted space. Let's go.
在一个未知的宇宙有秘密任务,出发
Really? That is so interesting.
是吗?好有意思喔
Would you like some tea, Mrs. Nesbitt?
你要喝点茶吗?纳斯比太太
Buzz!
巴斯
It's so nice you could join us on such late notice.
临时邀请你,你还能来真是太好了
- Oh, no! - What a lovely hat, Mrs. Nesbitt.
- 糟了 - 好可爱的帽子,纳斯比太太
It goes quite well with your head.
你戴起来真好看
Hannah! Oh, Hannah!
汉娜,汉娜
Mom? Please ex. Cuse me, ladies.
妈,失陪了,小姐们
I'll be right back.
我马上回来
What is it, Mom? Mom, where are you?
妈,什么事?妈,你在哪里?
Buzz. Hey. Buzz, are you okay?
巴斯,巴斯,你还好吧?
Gone! It's all gone.
完了,全都完了
All of it's gone. Bye- bye. See ya.
全都完了,再见,拜拜!
What happened to you?
你是怎么了?
One minute you're defending the whole galaxy.
前一分钟你还在捍卫全宇宙
And suddenly you find yourself suckin' down Darjeeling with
突然间,你就跟路易十六的王妃
Marie Antoinette and her little sister.
还有她的妹妹,坐在一起喝下午茶
I think you've had enough tea for today.
我想你今天,大概是茶喝得太多了
Let's get you outta here, Buzz.
快起来,跟我走吧,巴斯
Don't you get it? You see the hat?
你还不明白吗?看到帽子没有?
- I am Mrs. Nesbitt! - Snap out of it, Buzz!
- 我是纳斯比太太 - 清醒一点,巴斯
I'm sorry. I... You're right.
我...我很抱歉,你说的对
I am just a little depressed. That's all.
我只是有一点沮丧
I can get through this.
我可以熬过去的
Oh, I'm a sham!
我是个冒牌货
- Look at me. - Quiet, Buzz.
- 安静,巴斯 - 看看我
I can't even fly out of a window.
我甚至没有办法飞出窗外
The hat looked good? Tell me the hat looked good.
但是...这个帽子很好看,告诉我这个帽子很好看
Out the window!
飞出窗外！
Buzz, you're a genius!
巴斯,你是个天才
Come on, come on. This way.
快,跟我来
Years of academy, training, wasted!
几年的辛苦训练全浪费了
B- 3.
是B3
Miss! G- 6.
没中!G6
You sunk it. Are you peeking?
你猜对了,你是不是在偷看?
Oh, quit your whinin' and pay up. No, no, not the ear.
不要啰嗦了,快交出来,不...不要耳朵
- Give me the nose. Come on. - How about three out of five?
- 把鼻子给我,快点 - 五战三胜怎么样
Hey, guys! Guys! Hey!
各位!各位!
- Son of a building block. It's Woody. - He's in the psycho's bedroom.
- 我的老天爷,是胡迪 - 他在那个疯子的房间里
- Hi! - Everyone! It's Woody!
- 嗨! - 大伙儿,是胡迪
- Woody? - You're kidding!
- 胡迪 - 真的假的?
- Woody? - We're gonna get outta here, Buzz.
- 胡迪 - 我们要离开这儿了,巴斯
Buzz?
巴斯
- Hey, look! - Woody!
- 你们看 - 胡迪
Oh, boy, am I glad to see you guys.
老天,真高兴看到你们
- I knew you'd come back, Woody. - What are you doin' over there?
- 我就知道你会回来 - 你在那边做什么?
It's a long story, Bo. I'll ex. Plain later.
说来话长,宝贝,待会儿再说
Here! Catch this!
来,接好啊
- Whoa! I've got it, Woody. - He got it, Woody.
- 我接到了 - 他接到了,胡迪
Good goin', Slink. Now just, just tie it on to somethin'.
干得好,弹簧狗,快点找个东西绑在上面
Wait, wait, wait, wait. I got a better idea. How 'bout we don't?
等等...我有更好的点子,别听他的
- Hey! - Potato Head.
- 嘿! - 蛋头
Did you all take stupid pills this morning?
你们今天是不是,都吃了笨蛋药了?
Have you forgotten what he did to Buzz?
你们难道忘了,他是怎么对付巴斯的?
And now you wanna let him back over here?
让他回来这好吗?
No! No, no, no, no, no! You got it... You got it all wrong, Potato Head.
不...你...你全都误会了,蛋头
Buzz is fine. Buzz is right here. He's with me!
巴斯很好,巴斯在这儿跟我在一起
- You are a liar! - No, I'm not. Buzz, come over here.
- 你是一个骗子 - 不,我不是,巴斯,快过来
Tell the nice toys that you're... that you're not dead.
告诉那些好心的玩具,你...你并没有死
Buzz, will you get up here and give me a hand?
巴斯,快来助我一臂之力
That's very funny, Buzz.
你很幽默,巴斯
- This is serious! - Hey, Woody! Where'd ya go?
- 我是认真的 - 胡迪,你到哪儿去了?
He's lying. Buzz ain't there.
他骗人,巴斯不在那儿
Oh! Hi, Buzz!
哦,嗨,巴斯?
Why don't you say hello to the guys over there?
朋友都在对面,怎么不打个招呼呢?
Hiya, fellas! To infinity and beyond!
嗨!各位,飞向宇宙浩瀚无垠
Hey, look! It's Buzz!
你们看是巴斯耶
Hey, Buzz, let's show the guys our new secret best friends handshake.
巴斯,我们让好朋友们看看,我们刚刚学会的握手方式
Give me five, man!
来拍个手吧
Something's screwy here.
有点儿可疑
So you see we're friends now, guys. Aren't we, Buzz?
你们看我们现在是好朋友了,对吗,巴斯?
You bet. Give me a hug.
没错,给我个拥抱
Boy, I love you too.
老天啊,我也爱你
See? It is Buzz.
看,那是巴斯耶
- Now give back the lights, Potato Head. - Wait just a minute.
- 把那玩意儿给我,蛋头 - 你先等一下
- What are you tryin' to pull? - Nothing!
- 你到底想干什么啊? - 没什么
- Oh, that is disgusting. - Murderer!
- 真恶心耶 - 凶手
- No! No, no, no, no, no! - You murdering dog!
- 不,不... - 杀人凶手
- It's not what you think. I swear! - Save it for the jury.
- 事情不是这样,我发誓 - 留着对陪审团说吧
I hope Sid pulls your voice box. Out, ya creep.
希望阿薛挖出你的声音盒,浑球
No, no! No, no! Don't leave! Don't leave!
不...不要走,不要走
Ya gotta help us, please! You don't know what it's like over here!
你...你们得帮帮我们,你们不知道这里是什么样子
Come on. Let's get outta here.
好了,没什么好看的了
Go back to your lives, citizens. Show's over.
回去玩我们的吧,好戏演完
Come back! Slink!
回来!弹簧狗
Slink! Please! Please! Listen to me!
弹簧狗,拜托,拜托你听听我说
No! No! Come back!
不,不,回来
Slinky!
弹簧狗
Buzz! Go away!
巴斯!走开!
You disgusting freaks!
你们这些恶心的怪胎
All right, back! Back, you cannibals!
你们这些食人族快退后,快让开!
He is still alive, and you're not gonna get him, you monsters!
他还活着,你们休想吃掉他,怪物
What are you doin'?
你们在干什么?
Hey. Hey, they fix. Ed you.
他们把你修好了耶
But they're cannibals.
但是...他们是食人族
We saw them eat those other toys.
我们看到他们吃别的玩具
Sorry. I thought that you were gonna...
抱歉,我...我还以为你们想...
You know, you know, eat my friend.
...吃我的朋友
Hey, no, no, wait, hey!
等等,别走!
- What's wrong? - Sid?
- 怎么了? - 阿薛
Not now, Mom! I'm busy!
等一下,妈,我有事
- Sid! Buzz, come on! - You left that door open.
- 阿薛 - 巴斯,快点起来
Get up! Use your legs! Fine! Let Sid trash you! But don't blame me!
你快起来,好吧,阿薛把你给拆了,可别怪我
It came! It finally came!
寄来了,终于寄来了
"The Big One."
大飞弹
"Extremely dangerous.
本物品极度危险
Keep out of reach of children."
请勿让儿童触摸
Cool! What am I gonna blow?
酷毙了,我该炸什么呢?
Man. Hey, where's that wimpy cowboy doll?
那个胆小的牛仔娃娃呢
Yes. I've always wanted to put a spaceman into orbit.
好耶,我一直想把,太空人射入太空轨道
Now. Yes.
搞定了,好耶
Oh, no!
喔!不!
Oh, man!
很烦耶
Sid Phillips reporting.
阿薛报告
Launch of the shuttle has been delayed
由于发射地点天候不佳
due to adverse weather conditions at the launch site.
因此发射顺延
Tomorrow's forecast: Sunny.
明天天气预报,晴天
Sweet dreams.
祝你好梦
I looked everywhere, honey, but all I could find was your hat.
我到处都找过了,我只找到你的帽子而已
But what if we leave them behind?
如果他们被丢在这里怎么办?
Oh, don't worry, honey.
别担心
I'm sure we'll find Woody and Buzz before we leave tomorrow.
我们明天离开以前,一定会找到胡迪和巴斯的
(安弟的玩具)
I need air!
我需要空气
Will you quit movin' around?
你别动来动去的
I'm sorry. It's just that I get... I get so nervous before I travel.
对不起,只是我在旅行之前,会非常的紧张
How did I get stuck with you as a moving buddy?
我怎么会选你当搬家伙伴
Everyone else was picked.
其他人都被选光了
Oh, Woody.
哦,胡迪
If only you could see how much Andy misses you.
如果你能看到安弟,他有多想你那就好了
Hey, Buzz!
嘿,巴斯
Hey. Get over here and see if you can get this toolbox. Off me.
快过来帮我搬走这个工具箱
Oh, come on, Buzz, I...
拜托,巴斯
Buzz, I can't do this without you. I need your help.
巴斯,没有你我办不到,我需要你的帮忙
I can't help. I can't help anyone.
我帮不了你,我帮不了任何人
Why, sure you can, Buzz. You can get me outta here.
你当然可以,巴斯,你可以把我弄出去
Then I'll get that rocket off you, and we'll make a break for Andy's house.
然后我替你拆掉火箭,然后我们逃回安弟家去
Andy's house, Sid's house. What's the difference?
安弟家,阿薛家,有什么差别呢?
Oh, Buzz. You've had a big fall. You must not be thinking clearly.
巴斯,你八成摔傻了,摔得脑筋都不清楚了
No, Woody. For the first time I am thinking clearly.
不,胡迪,我的头脑第一次这么清楚
You were right all along. I'm not a Space Ranger.
你说得对,我不是什么太空骑警
I'm just a toy, a stupid, little, insignificant toy.
我只是一个玩具,一个愚蠢微不足道的玩具
Whoa, hey, wait a minute.
等一下,想想看
Bein' a toy is a lot better than bein' a, a Space Ranger.
当一个玩具,要比当什么太空骑警好多了
- Yeah, right. - No, it is.
- 才怪 - 我说真的
Look, over in that house is a kid who thinks you are the greatest.
听着,在那个房子里面,有个小孩认为你是最棒的
And it's not because you're a Space Ranger, pal.
那可不是因为你是太空骑警
It's because you're a toy. You are his toy.
而是因为你是玩具,你是他的玩具
But why would Andy want me?
安弟为什么会想要我呢?
Why would Andy want you? Look at you! You're a Buzz Lightyear.
安弟为什么会想要你?看看你自己,你是巴斯光年
Any other toy would give up his moving parts just to be you.
任何玩具,都愿意被改造成像你一样
You've got wings. You glow in the dark. You talk!
你有飞翼,在黑暗中闪光,还会说话
Your helmet does that, that, that whoosh thing.
你的头盔还会...那样...那样打开来
You are a cool toy.
你是一个很酷的玩具
As a matter of fact, you're too cool.
老实说你真的是酷毙了
I mean, I mean, what chance does a toy like me have
我在想...像我这种普通的玩具
against a Buzz Lightyear action figure?
怎么跟你这么有名的,巴斯光年来比呢?
All I can do is...
我了不起只会说...
∮ There's a snake in my boots ∮
我的靴子里有蛇
Why would Andy ever want to play with me
安弟只要有了你就夠了
when he's got you?
怎么还会喜欢我呢?
I'm the one that should be strapped to that rocket.
我才应该被绑在火箭上
(安弟)
Listen, Buzz, forget about me.
听好,巴斯,不要管我了
You should get outta here while you can.
趁还来得及你赶快离开吧
Buzz? What are you doin'? I thought you were...
巴斯,你在干什么?我以为...
Come on, sheriff. There's a kid over in that house who needs us.
来吧,警长,对面有个需要我们的孩子
Now let's get you out of this thing.
让我先把你弄出来
Yes, sir!
是,遵命
Come on, Buzz. We can do it.
加油,巴斯,我们办得到
(搬家公司)
Woody, it's the moving van.
胡迪,搬家货车到了
We gotta get outta here now.
我们必须快点离开
Come on, Buzz.
加油,巴斯
All right.
好了
- Hey, I'm out! - Almost there.
- 巴斯,我出来了 - 快成功了
I want to ride the pony.
我要骑小马
Woody? Woody? Are you all right?
胡迪,胡迪,你没事吧?
I'm fine. I'm okay.
我没事,我很好
Oh, yeah! Time for lift- off!
对了,该发射了
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇宙浩瀚无垠
Back, back.
退后...
Down, down!
走开,走开
Okay, what do I do? Come on, Woody. Think.
我该怎么办?加油,胡迪,想啊,想啊
Guys!
各位
No, no, no, no! Wait! Wait. Listen, please.
不...等等,不要走,听我说
There's a good toy down there, and he's gonna be blown to bits in a few minutes.
巴斯是个好玩具,再过几分钟他就会被炸得粉碎
All because of me. We gotta save him.
都是因为我,我们必须救他
And... But I need your help.
但是我需要你们的帮忙
Please. He's my friend.
拜托,他是我的朋友
And he's the only one I've got.
我就只剩这么一个朋友
Thank you. Okay, I think I know what to do.
谢谢,好了,我知道该怎么做
We're gonna have to break a few rules.
我们要打破一些小规则
But if it works, it'll help everybody.
如果成功了,这对我们大家都好
(安弟的玩具)
Houston to Mission Control. Come in, Control.
休士顿呼叫管制塔,请回答
Launch pad is being constructed.
发射台已架设好了
All right, listen up.
好,听清楚了
I need Pump Boy here, Ducky here.
我要帮浦到这里,鸭子到这儿
Legs, you're with Ducky.
长腿跟鸭子一组
RollerBob and I don't move 'til we get the signal. Clear?
我跟滑板听到讯号声才出动,懂吗?
Okay. Let's move!
好了,行动吧!
Wind the frog.
替青蛙上发条
Wait for the signal.
等他的信号
Go!
上吧
All right, let's go!
好了,我们走
I'll get it!
我来吧
Now!
冲啊
I'm coming. I'm coming.
来了,来了
Scud!
阿德!
Stupid dog.
大笨狗
Lean back!
往后仰!
Mission Control, is the launch pad construction complete?
管制塔,发射台已经完工了吗?
Roger. Rocket is now secured to guide wire.
收到了,火箭现在已接到导引线
We are currently obtaining the ignition sticks.
我们现在正在装置,点火装置杆
Countdown will commence momentarily.
马上就会开始倒数计时
- Stand by. - Let's go.
- 待命 - 我们上吧
Hey, Ma! Where are the matches? Oh, wait. Here they are. Never mind.
妈,火柴在哪里?在这里,我找到了
Woody! Great! Help me outta this thing.
胡迪,太好了,快点帮我弄开
- What? - It's okay. Everything's under control.
- 什么? - 别担心,我有锦囊妙计
Woody, what are you doing?
胡迪,你在干什么?
Houston. All systems are go. Requesting permission to launch...
休士顿,所有系统正常,请求允许发射
Hey? How'd you get out here?
你怎么会在这里?
Oh, well. You and I can have a cookout later.
好吧,我们等一下可以烤肉
Houston, do we have permission to launch?
休士顿,我们可以发射了吗?
Roger. Permission granted.
收到了,请求照准
You are confirmed at "T" minus ten seconds.
倒数十秒后就可以发射了
And counting. Ten, nine,
倒数十秒,十,九...
eight, seven, six,
八,七,六...
five, four, three, two,
五,四,三,二...
- one! - Reach for the sky!
- 一! - 把手举起来
This town ain't big enough for the two of us.
你休想在这里为非作歹
What?
什么啊?
Somebody's poisoned the water hole.
有人对水源下了毒
- It's busted. - Who are you callin' busted buster?
- 它坏掉了 - 是谁说我坏掉了?
That's right.
没错
I'm talking to you Sid Phillips.
我是在跟你说话,阿薛菲利普
We don't like bein' blown up Sid
我们不想被炸掉
or smashed or ripped apart.
不想被打烂,也不想被拆开
- "We"? - That's right! Your toys!
- 我们? - 没错,你的玩具们
Mama!
妈妈
Mama! Mama!
妈妈...
Mama!
妈妈
From now on you must take good care of your toys!
从现在起,你得好好照顾你的玩具
Because if you don't we'll find out Sid.
如果你不照做,我们会知道,阿薛
We toys can see everything.
我们玩具可以看到一切事情
So play nice.
所以你要乖一点
We did it! We did it! Yes!
成功了!办到了!
The toys! The toys are alive!
那些玩具...他们是活的
Nice toy.
娃娃乖乖
What's wrong, Sid?
阿薛,你是怎么了?
Don't you want to play with Sally?
你不想跟莎莉玩吗?
Nice work, fellows. Good job.
干得好,各位,非常好
Comin' out of the ground, what a touch. That was a stroke of genius.
我们合作愉快,真的是太精采了
Woody.
胡迪
Thanks.
谢了
Everybody say, "Bye, house!"
跟房子说再见
- Woody! The van! - Bye, house.
- 胡迪,你看 - 再见
We gotta run! Thanks, guys!
我们得走了,谢了,各位
Quick!
快点
Just go. I'll catch up.
你先走,我会赶上的
(搬运专家  从东岸到西岸)
Come on!
快来吧
You can do it, Woody!
胡迪,你办得到的
I got it!
我抓到了
I made it.
我成功了
Get away, you stupid dog! Down!
走开,你这只笨狗,走开,走开
- Down! - Hold on, Woody!
- 不要,不要 - 胡迪,撑着点
I can't do it.
我...我撑不住了
Take care of Andy for me!
替我照顾安弟
No!
不!
Buzz!
巴斯
Are we there already?
已经到了吗?
- Woody? - How did you?
- 胡迪 - 你怎么会跑来?
- How'd he get here? - Where have you?
- 胡迪,你是怎么来的? - 你到哪儿去了?
What happened?
出了什么事?
- What's goin' on? - What's he takin'?
- 怎么了 - 他在干什么?
There you are!
找到了
Hey. What's he doing?
他在干什么啊?
He's at it again!
啊!他又杀人了
- Get him! - Come on!
- 快去抓他 - 快点
No, no!
不,不
No, no, no, no! Wait! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
不...等等...
Pig pile!
胖猪,压顶
- Get outta that car! - Move it!
- 快点下车 - 快点
No! Please! You don't understand!
等等,你们不明白
Buzz is out there. We gotta help him.
巴斯有危险,我们得帮他
- No! - Toss him overboard!
- 不要,住手 - 这个杀人凶手,把他丢下去
No, no, no! Wait!
不要,住手
- Hooray! - So long, Woody!
- 好耶 - 胡迪,再见啦
Oh! Woody!
胡迪!
- Oh! Well, thanks for the ride. - Look out!
- 谢谢你让我搭便车 - 小心!
Now let's catch up to that truck.
好了,我们快去追那辆卡车
(涡轮引擎)
(杂物)
Guys! Guys! Woody's riding R.C.
各位,各位,胡迪在开遥控车
- What? - And Buzz is with him!
- 巴斯跟他在一起 - 什么?
It is Buzz!
真的是巴斯
Woody was telling the truth.
胡迪说的是实话
- What have we done? - Great! Now I have guilt.
- 我们做了什么啊? - 这下好了,我有罪恶感
We're almost there!
我们就快要到了
Rocky, the ramp!
洛基,放下斜坡
(升降机)
Look out!
小心
Quick! Hold onto my tail!
快点,抓住我的尾巴
- Attaboy, Slink! - Oh! Woody!
- 干得好,弹簧狗 - 胡迪
Woody! Speed up!
胡迪,加速啊
- Speed up! - The batteries! They're runnin' out!
- 加速 - 电池已经没有电了
∮ Hakuna Matata ∮
∮ 哈库拉,玛塔塔 ∮
∮ What a wonderful phrase ∮
∮ 多棒的一句话 ∮
- I can't hold on much longer. - Slink! Hang on!
- 我快撑不下去了 - 弹簧狗,你要撑住
Great!
这下好了
Woody! The rocket!
胡迪,火箭
The match! Yes!
火柴,好耶
Thank you, Sid!
谢了,阿薛
No! No, no! No!
不...
No! Oh, no!
No, no, no, no, no,
不...不...
no!
不!
No!
- Woody! What are you doing? - Hold still, Buzz!
- 胡迪,你在干什么? - 巴斯,不要动
You did it!
你办到了
Next stop. Andy!
下一站...安弟
Wait a minute. I just lit a rocket. Rockets ex. Plode!
等一下,我刚刚点着了火箭,火箭会爆炸
I should have held on longer.
我应该多撑几秒的
Look! Look! It's Woody and Buzz comin' up fast!
你们看,胡迪和巴斯冲过来了
Woody!
好耶,胡迪
Take cover!
快找掩护
This is the part where we blow up!
我们会被炸成碎片
Not today!
今天不会
Hey, Buzz! You're flyin'!
巴斯,你在飞行
This isn't flying. This is falling with style.
这不叫飞行,这叫做摔得很炫
To infinity and beyond!
飞向宇宙浩瀚无垠
Buzz, we missed the truck.
巴斯,我们超过卡车了
We're not aiming for the truck.
我们并不是要到卡车上
Hey, wow!
嘿,哇赛
- What? What is it? - Woody! Buzz!
- 怎么了? - 胡迪,巴斯
Oh, great, you found them. Where were they?
太好了,你找到了,它们在哪儿?
- Here in the car! - See?
- 就在车上 - 看吧
Now, what'd I tell you? Right where you left 'em.
我就跟你说过你会找到的
- Which one can I open first? - Let's let Molly open one.
- 妈咪,我先拆哪一个? - 让茉莉拆一个礼物
Frankincense this is Myrrh.
牛奶,听到请回答
Hey, heads up, everybody. It's show time.
大伙儿,注意,好戏上场了
Whoa! It's time!
快过去
Oh, Bo.
宝贝
There's got to be a less painful way to get my attention.
你下次叫我,能不能试着温柔点?
Merry Christmas, sheriff.
警长,圣诞快乐
Say, isn't that mistletoe?
那不是檞寄生吗?
Maybe Andy will get another dinosaur. Like a leaf eater.
也许安弟会有一只新的恐龙,草食性恐龙
That way I could play the dominant predator.
那样我就能当...可怕的肉食动物
Quiet, everyone! Quiet!
安静,各位安静
Molly's first present is Mrs. Potato Head.
茉莉的第一件礼物是...蛋头太太
Repeat: A Mrs. Potato Head.
重复,蛋头太太
Way to go, Idaho!
恭喜你,蛋头兄
Gee, I'd better shave.
我该刮胡子了
Come in Frankincense.
牛奶,请回答
Andy is now opening his first present.
安弟现在正在拆,他的第一个礼物
- It's... - Buzz. Buzz Lightyear,
- 那是... - 巴斯,巴斯光年
- I can't quite... - you are not worried, are you?
- 我不太明白... - 你不会是在担心吧?
- Me? No, no. - Make out...
- 我,不是... - 被挡住了
No. No, no, no, no.
不...不...
A large bo... It's...
那是一个很大的盒子,那是...
- Are you? - Now, Buzz,
- 你呢? - 巴斯
what could Andy possibly get that is worse than you?
不管安弟得到的什么礼物,都不会比你更糟了
Oh what is it? What is it?
那是什么,是什么?
Wow! A puppy!
哇,一只小狗狗
∮ You've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 你有我的朋友 ∮
∮ When the road looks rough ahead ∮
∮ 当前面的路看起来很崎岖时 ∮
∮ And you're miles and miles from your nice warm bed ∮
∮ 你离温暖的床越来越远了 ∮
∮ You just remember what your old pal said ∮
∮ 你只记得你的老朋友说过什么 ∮
∮ Boy you've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 孩子，你有我的朋友 ∮
∮ Yeah you've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 是的，你有我的朋友 ∮
∮ You've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 你有我的朋友 ∮
∮ You got troubles And I got 'em too ∮
∮ 你有麻烦，我也有 ∮
∮ There isn't anything I wouldn't do for you ∮
∮ 我不会为你做任何事 ∮
∮ If we stick together we can see it through ∮
∮ 如果我们团结在一起，我们就能看穿它 ∮
∮ 'Cause you've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 因为我是你的朋友 ∮
∮ You've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 你有我的朋友 ∮
∮ Some other folks might be a little bit smarter than I am ∮
∮ 其他人可能比我聪明一点 ∮
∮ Bigger and stronger too ∮
∮ 也更大更强 ∮
∮ Maybe ∮
∮ 也许吧 ∮
∮ But none of them will ever love you the way I do ∮
∮ 但是没有人会像我那样爱你 ∮
∮ It's me and you boy ∮
∮ 是我和你 ∮
∮ And as the years go by ∮
∮ 随着岁月的流逝 ∮
∮ Our friendship will never die ∮
∮ 我们的友谊永不消逝 ∮
∮ You're gonna see it's our destiny ∮
∮ 你会看到这是我们的命运 ∮
∮ You've got a friend in me ∮
∮ 你有我的朋友 ∮